<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Nick's Site]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Nick's Site]]></description>
        <link>http://nickrance.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:24:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://nickrance.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:24:41 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skills]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/d7274d49-a386-43be-a142-349b7b724e5e.png" title="Nicholas Rance" alt="Full Stack Web Developer / Data Scientist">,<h2>Skills</h2>,<h3>Machine Learning</h3>,<p>I’m familiar with most modern ML Frameworks such as Tensorflow and Caffe. I am always eagerly looking for creative applications of ML and Data Science.</p>,<p><strong>Featured Project: <a href="https://devpost.com/software/machine-learning-psychology-for-water-sustainability" title="Devpost Link">WaterSavr</a> - HackNYU Sustainabilty and Social Impact Prize Winner</strong></p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/365e9f70-48fe-430b-9591-dfcdc71ae6a8.png">,<p>The goal of this project was the measure the amount of water being used from microphone input. I created a dataset of a few dozen audio files for each of 3 common water appliances (faucets, showers and toilets) and trained a model to classify audio sounds as being one of the three appliances or neither. As it was a hackathon project, the accuracy rates left a little bit to be desired but audio processing the model was be able predict with about 65% accuracy the source of the water. The next step was using the duration of the water flow and the appliance being used to calculate the amount of water being used. For this naive implementation I simply looked up the flow rates for each appliance I tested with at NYU but a more sophisticated model may be able to predict usage without this feature.</p>,<h3>Embedded Software Development</h3>,<p>I have experience developing software for the Raspberry Pi single board computers and the Arduino embedded computer</p>,<p><strong>Featured Project: <a href="http://kidswrite.org/" title="">KidsWrite</a></strong></p>,<p>KidsWrite is a non-profit organization which uses computing and digital libraries to increase access to books for children in Haiti. When I joined the project they were interested in migrating their digital library system from OLPCs (One Laptop per Child)  to a muse of a ore portable and scalable architecture. I proposed the use of the Raspberry Pi 3B as a server and wireless router and inexpensive android tablets as clients. I then configured the RPi as a server that could run on portable power (external battery pack) as power is often intermittent in Haiti. I also configured the Android tablets with simple portal applications to access the Pi hosted applications.</p>,<h3>Drone/Robotics Development</h3>,<p>I’ve developed programs for the Parrot ARDrone2.0 and have experience working with the DJI Phantom line of drones.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9540f0e3-348a-4a1b-a655-f20de817dadb.jpg" title="Sample Command: &quot;Drone, do a backflip&quot;" alt="Borrowed my hairstyle from the 80s">,<p><strong>Featured Project - #DroneGoals - TribeHacks 2016 3rd Place</strong></p>,<p>Developed a voice command API for the ARDrone2.0 allowing it to perform various motor functions and acrobatic stunts without the need for manual control. We also implemented naive object tracking and following using openCV.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://nickrance.com/skills/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9c75b54c-6dc6-4483-a1f5-1c392fdf260d</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 23:55:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NickRance (Nicholas Rance)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>NickRance (Nicholas Rance)</h1><p>NickRance has 11 repositories available. Follow their code on GitHub.</p><img src="https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/11139430?v=3&s=400"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/NickRance</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">aa2165f7-5021-43d9-b953-aeb337a3b871</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 15:14:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Test]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>more blah blah</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://nickrance.com/improving-literacy-in-haiti-using-low-cost-technology/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3d1c66c0-3d76-46cd-99e9-6ff1c41f2a52</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 16:26:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Placeholder]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Placeholder</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://nickrance.com/placeholder/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5a4de822-35f3-44e7-871f-6ef60e2c0c99</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 02:05:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>